<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>*nix on X&amp;R</title><link>https://www.xnr.one/categories/nix/</link><description>Recent content in *nix on X&amp;R</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.xnr.one/categories/nix/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>First Look at KDE Plasma</title><link>https://www.xnr.one/post/first-look-at-kde-plasma/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.xnr.one/post/first-look-at-kde-plasma/</guid><description>Hello once again! Today we will discus what is KDE Plasma and it&amp;rsquo;s defaults.
What is KDE Plasma: KDE Plasma is an desktop environment created by KDE Foundation. Lets dissect that line first. What is a desktop environment?
A desktop environment is basically your operating systems graphical interface. It gets info from your computer and shows you as images and symbols. Without an graphical interface you will only see white letters on a black screen.</description></item><item><title>What *nix Should You Use?</title><link>https://www.xnr.one/post/what-nix-should-you-use/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.xnr.one/post/what-nix-should-you-use/</guid><description>Hello again, today I&amp;rsquo;ll explain why and which *nix distribution I use.
Distribution? What is that? As I said in my last blog post, *nix isn&amp;rsquo;t a single operating system but more of a standard for an operating system family. The most important two main branches of this family are BSD and Linux. For example Mac OS X is a BSD distribution and Ubuntu is a Linux distribution I won&amp;rsquo;t try to write the whole distribution tree because that will take ages but this image may give you an idea.</description></item><item><title>Why Do People Use *nix?</title><link>https://www.xnr.one/post/why-do-people-use-nix/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.xnr.one/post/why-do-people-use-nix/</guid><description>Hello there, this is my first post and I want to explain some things about my *nix usage.
Cool but what is *nix? *nix is an acronym for &amp;ldquo;Unix-like operating system&amp;rdquo;. An operating system simply put is a container for programs for you to use. I mean, It&amp;rsquo;s actually way more than that but lets start simple shall we? Take Windows for example. You can&amp;rsquo;t run your Windows programs without running windows can you?</description></item></channel></rss>